Harriet Gray Blackwell Papers
Harriet Gray Blackwell Papers
1919-1983
Blackwell, Harriet (Gray)
3.5 linear ft.
Papers of the American author and poet. Collection includes biographical material, correspondence, writings, and memorabilia.
148852
Biographical History
Harriet Gray Blackwell was an American author and poet. She wrote several novels, and her work appeared in many national magazines including Good Housekeeping, Saturday Evening Post, and others.
Scope and Contents of the Collection
The Harriet Gray Blackwell Papers consist of biographical material, correspondence, writings, and memorabilia.
Subject files contain biographical material and a few photographs.
Correspondence spans fifty years and includes individuals, academic institutions, and publishing companies.
Writings contains typescripts, manuscripts, galleys and other formats for articles, books, poetry, and short stories.
Memorabilia includes awards, clippings, class notes, financial and legal papers, reviews, and a speech given at Columbia College Commencement in 1961.
Arrangement of the Collection
All material is arranged in alphabetical order by name, title or subject.
Subject and Genre Headings
Literature -- American Fiction; Literature -- American Poetry; Women Authors; Blackwell, Harriet (Gray); Poets, American.; American poetry -- Women authors.; Women poets, American.; American poetry -- 20th century.; Women authors, American.; Correspondence.; Clippings (information artifacts); Speeches (documents); Manuscripts for publication.; Galley proofs.; Photographs.; Authors.; Poets.
Access Restrictions
The majority of our archival and manuscript collections are housed offsite and require advanced notice for retrieval. Researchers are encouraged to contact us in advance concerning the collection material they wish to access for their research.
Acquisition Information
Gift of Harriet Gray Blackwell, 1970-1986.
Inventory
- Subject files
  - Biographical material (Box 1)
  - Photographs (Box 1)
- Correspondence
  - Bogan, Louise, 1954 (Box 1)
  - Columbia College, 1961-1970 (Box 1)
  - Cousins, Margaret, 1945-1972; undated; 4 folders (Box 1)
  - Dietz Press Inc., 1954-1976; undated; 3 folders (Box 1)
  - General, 1938-1982; undated; 14 folders (Box 1)
- Writings
  - Articles
    - Typescripts, A-Z, untitled, 27 folders (Box 1)
    - Printed material, A-Z, 4 folders (Box 1)
    - Miscellaneous articles (Oversize 1)
      Archibald Rutledge and his home; Green gold of Redlands building new colony; My place in the sun; Southern personalities (Wil Lou Gray)
  - Books
    - The Book of Trees, manuscript (Box 1)
    - A Candle for All Time, manuscript; 8 folders (Box 1)
    - The Leaf -- Green Fire, manuscript (Box 2)
    - The Redoubtable Lucy, manuscript; 5 folders (Box 2)
    - The Trees of Heaven, manuscript, galleys, published material; 4 folders (Box 2)
    - The Winter Tree, manuscript, galleys, published material; 4 folders (Box 2)
    - The Word, the Flowers and the Silver Pear, manuscript (Box 2)
  - Poetry
    - Notes, A-Z, untitled, 5 folders (Box 2)
    - Notebook (Box 2)
    - Typescripts, A-Z, untitled, 8 folders (Box 2)
    - Notebook I-IV, 4 folders (Box 2)
    - Published material, A-Z, untitled, 5 folders (Box 2)
    - Miscellaneous poetry (Oversize 1)
  - Stories
    - A-G, 11 folders (Box 2)
    - H-W, 20 folders (Box 3)
    - Anecdotes (Box 3)
    - Bibliography (Box 3)
    - Notes A-Z, untitled, 3 folders (Box 3)
    - Notebook (Box 3)
    - Outlines, A-Z, untitled, 2 folders (Box 3)
    - Research material, 2 folders (Box 3)
    - Rough drafts, A-Z, untitled, 4 folders (Box 3)
- Memorabilia
  - Acceptance/rejection memoranda (Box 3)
  - Acceptance/rejection memoranda, file cards (Box 4)
  - Awards, 1943-1982; undated (Box 3)
  - Clippings, 1936-1975; undated; 5 folders (Box 3)
  - Course notes, 14 folders (Box 3)
  - Financial (Box 3)
  - Legal (Box 3)
  - Printed material, 3 folders (Box 3)
  - Reviews (Box 3)
  - Speech, Columbia College Commencement, 1961 (Box 3)
  - Miscellaneous (Oversize 1)